Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 20.
We are asked to find the time complexity of the square root function.
It took to meet our intention and calculate the square root of this number.
OK, so I want from you to pause the video and think about it, how to solve this exercise and how to
find the time complex.
I hope you solve it correctly.
Please write your solution in the comments below before we continue.
So.
Let's start.
For we have it for you, and we return to state.
Four.
And guess equal to one.
This is the initial condition.
Guess times guess less than or equal to n, this is the fire, this is the final or the stopping condition.
And guess plus plus is the increment function or increment?
OK.
Inside the loop, there is an ordinary if statement and the checking just guess times guess which is
guess square equal equal to n return.
And guess this is of one.
And return minus one is of one.
OK, so the follow up here will determine the complexity of this function.
Let me take an example here.
In order to better, better understand and then calculate the complexity.
Guests will start from one 10 guest square less than or equal to N, and it is plus plus it's going
to pass through all the elements from one.
They'll guess the square.
OK, now.
Let's start by taking an equal to five and equal to five.
And gas equal to one guess.
Square less than equal to one.
And guess plus plus.
OK, we start from one.
This is the iteration.
And guess.
And the result.
And the first iteration and equal to one.
Guess times, guess one.
This is Guest Square Guest Square is equal to one because we start from one and an equal to five, sorry.
Sorry, yes.
It's an equal to five.
So guess the square less than five.
Yes, it will go and and execute this if guests square equal, equal to and return gas.
Otherwise, it will not do anything so it will not do anything again.
Goes up and still equal to five guests.
A square, yes, is increased by one.
Now, gas is equal to two.
Two times two is equal to four, so guests squared is equal to four for less than five.
Yes, it goes here.
Guests two squared, equal, equal to and return and guests.
No, it is not the case.
So we have four square for equal, equal to five.
No.
So it will not execute anything.
Here it will increase gas by one going up.
And equal to five, guess now equal to three three square is equal to nine, so nine less than.
Or equal to five?
No, so it will stop that count the loop, it will break outside the loop and it will return minus one.
Now.
What we have done here.
It will execute him two times.
If an equal to five.
OK.
If an equal to six.
It would execute.
Let me show you if an equal to six and g squared would be start from one for.
Nine.
16.
OK, because Foursquare is equal to 16, it would execute four times.
OK, so one and equal to five is executed three, two times one and equal to six.
It is executing three times.
OK.
Now, if an equal to seven, it would execute, like about four times.
So what is the relation?
We are executing and we are looping this from one Del Radican, and there's on that radical act because
we are getting that at the square root of gas, a square against the square and it is less than an.
So it's very simple.
Yes, the square.
Equal to N G, equal radical, and we are moving from one to radical and more radical and or it is from
one to G.
OK.
It's very simple.
We have solved this.
There's all of that can and because we are not depending on.
We are depending on N and we need to get.
And so in order to get and we need to make an equal quest.
OK, so we here we have the stopping condition is Jisc, where less than or equal to n.
So and what the result and je radical or radical and equal to G.